Register of the Leopold Labedz papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Leopold Labedz papers
1860-1996
89018
Hoover Institution Archives
140 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize boxes (64.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, serial issues, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, and motion picture film relating to political and cultural conditions in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, Soviet and Eastern European dissidents, Russian and Eastern European literature, post-World War II international relations, and the nature and history of communism and Marxian theory. Includes manuscripts submitted to Survey for publication, correspondence with contributors, and financial and other records of the journal.
Labedz, Leopold, 1920-1993.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of the motion picture film in this collection are available for immediate access. To access sound or video recordings during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1989.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Leopold Labedz was born on January 22, 1920, in Simbirsk, Russia, but spent most of his childhood in Warsaw, where both of his parents were well-respected physicians. Labedz studied at the Kreczmara Gymnasium and subsequently, in 1937, continued his education at the University of Warsaw. By mid-1938, he had relocated to Paris to study medicine at the Sorbonne. The exposure to French culture quickly shifted his interests from medicine to the humanities and to political philosophy in particular. However, the events of World War II stalled Labedz's academic pursuits.
While on summer vacation in Poland, World War II broke out. Labedz’s father, who was in the Polish military medical service, was recruited by the Soviet army to act as a head-physician of a military hospital in Eastern Poland. Since Labedz’s mother died when he was very young, he joined his father at the hospital as its librarian. By 1941, in the course of numerous relocations of the hospital, 21-year-old Leopold was separated from his father. As a result, he joined the Polish Army, led by General Anders.
When the war was over, instead of returning to Poland, Labedz reunited with his father in London. In the early 1950s he decided to continue his studies by enrolling at the London School of Economics. There he obtained his bachelor of science degree in economics, while never losing sight of his love for the social sciences. In 1955, Labedz founded the quarterly journal Survey, which he edited for 25 years. The journal primarily focused on Soviet studies and the world of communism and was considered to be the authoritative publication on the subject. The journal folded in the 1980s, mainly due to lack of funding and Labedz’s ailing health.
Leopold Labedz died in March 1993.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Leopold Labedz papers are comprised of biographical documents, correspondence, conference materials, radio and television broadcasts, speeches and writings, subject files, administrative records of Survey journal, writings submitted to the journal for publication, photographs, slides, other audiovisual materials, and printed matter.
The collection documents the personal and professional life of Leopold Labedz and includes information on the administrative activities of Survey journal, as well as its relation to the Congress for Cultural Freedom.
Labedz's original order was retained when possible.
Soviet Union--Politics and government.; Soviet Union--Civilization.; Dissenters--Soviet Union.; Russian literature.; Europe, Eastern--Politics and government--1945-; Europe, Eastern--Civilization.; Dissenters--Europe, Eastern.; European literature.; World politics--1945-1989.; Communism.; Journalists.
- Biographical File, 1938-1989
  - Application for lecture appointment in Australia, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Biographical sketches, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes curriculum vitae and biographical information on Leopold Labedz.
  - Certificate of naturalization, 1948-1954 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    Includes related documents and correspondence regarding the naturalization process.
  - Diary, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Diploma, London School of Economics, 1953 August 15 (Oversize-box 142)
  - Education, 1938-1957 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Includes a student handbook, student union membership cards, report card offprints, recommendation for admission to the London School of Economics, and matriculation records.
  - Interviews and talks with Labedz, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Labedz, Jakub, Dr., undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Includes luggage tags and postcard confirming Jakub Labedz opened an x-ray consulting room in London after World War II.
  - Memberships, 1957-1975 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Ministry of Labour and National Service, circa 1953 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    Comprised of employment appointment cards.
  - Personal data sheet, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Pretura Unificata Di Bologna: Atto Di Notorieta, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    Includes an attested affidavit from the Unified Local Court of Bologna.
- Correspondence, 1926-1992
  Personal and professional correspondence documenting the private life of Leopold Labedz as well as his professional career as it pertains to Survey journal. The files in this series are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent. When possible, Labedz's original order was maintained.
  - Abe, Masatoshi, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Abraham, S. R., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Abramovitch, R., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Abramovitz, Irving, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Acheson, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Adamthwaite, A. P., 1979 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Adomeit, Hannes, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Agnieszka, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Agouri, Y., 1961 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Agursky, Mikhail, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Ahmed, Mahamoud Sheikh, undated (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Aldor, George, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Aldrich, Nelson W., Jr., 1960 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Aldus, Anthony, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Alevizos, T. G., 1972 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Alexander, B. H., 1961 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Alexandrova, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Alexeyeva, Ludmila, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Alfred, undated (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Allen, Margaret, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Allen, Richard, 1981 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Allworth, Edward, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Alsop, Joseph, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Alsterdal, Alvir, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Amalrik, Andrey A., 1977-1981 (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Aman, Thomas L., 1970 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Amirsadeghi, Hossein, 1981 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Anderson, Gillian, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Anderson, Trond, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Andreski, S. L., 1970-1985 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Andrey, Amalrik, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Anin, David, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 43)
  - Apostol, Pavel, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - Appleton, Michael, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - Arai, Ryo, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 46)
  - Are, Giuseppe, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Arima, Tatsuo, 1971, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Armaud, Dan and Carol, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - Armes, Keith, Dr., 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1: 50)
  - Armstrong, John A., 1975 (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Arnold, Mary, undated (Box-folder 1: 52)
  - Arnold, Melvin, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 53)
  - Arnovitz, Benton M., 1986 (Box-folder 1: 54)
  - Arnstein, Walter L., 1975 (Box-folder 1: 55)
  - Aron, Raymond, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 1: 56)
  - Aronsfield, C. C., 1979 (Box-folder 1: 57)
  - Aronson, Michael, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 58)
  - Ascher, Abraham, 1978 (Box-folder 1: 59)
  - Ashbee, Felicity, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 60)
  - Asker, Julie, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1: 61)
  - Aspaturian, Vernon V., 1962-1974 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Asquith, Ivon, 1979 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Assheton, Betty M., 1974 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Atkin, Muriel, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Atwater, Arlene, 1976 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Atwater, Jim, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Austrian Institute, 1976 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Azrael, Jeremy R., 1962 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - A - general, 1961-1986 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Babel, Natalie, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Bachman, Marta, 1976 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Bäckström, Johannes, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Bader, William B., 1973 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Bahr, K., 1960 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Bailey, George, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Baker, Eric, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Baker, Liena, undated (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Baker, Meriel W., 1966 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Baker, Sandra, 1974 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Balawyder, A., Dr., 1970 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Balcells, Carmen, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Bale, Cliff, 1974 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Bane, Janet D., 1970 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Banfi, Ludovico, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Barbara, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - Barber, J. D., 1975-1979 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - Bardache, Judy, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Barghoorn, Frederick C., 1970 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Barlow, P., 1978 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Barnett, J. H., 1958 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Barnett, Roger, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - Baron, Murray, 1985 (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - Bartels, Ursula, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - Bartley, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - Baske, S., Dr., 1971 (Box-folder 2: 35)
  - Bass, Alma, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 36)
  - Bass, Robert, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 2: 37)
  - Bauer, Peter, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 2: 38)
  - Bauman, Zygmunt, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2: 39)
  - BBC news organizer, 1968, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 40)
  - Beam, Jacob, 1975 (Box-folder 2: 41)
  - Beaven, John, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 42)
  - Beavers, William R., 1974 (Box-folder 2: 43)
  - Beavin, Helen I., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 44)
  - Beck, R. C., 1972 (Box-folder 2: 45)
  - Beedham, Brian, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 46)
  - Bell, Carol, 1975 (Box-folder 2: 47)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1957-1979 (Box-folder 2: 48)
  - Bell, J. G., 1970-1973 (Box-folder 2: 49)
  - Bell, Pearl K., 1977 (Box-folder 2: 50)
  - Bellehumeur, Josee, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 51)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 2: 52)
  - Belnikov, N., 1976 (Box-folder 2: 53)
  - Ben, Francine, 1978 (Box-folder 2: 54)
  - Ben-Shlomo, Ze'ev, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 55)
  - Bender, Peter, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 56)
  - Bender, Ryszard, undated (Box-folder 2: 57)
  - Bendix, Reinhardt, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 58)
  - Benenson, Peter, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 59)
  - Bennigsen, A., 1959 (Box-folder 2: 60)
  - Bensen, Donald R., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 61)
  - Benson, Brian, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 62)
  - Bent, Evelyn, 1963 (Box-folder 2: 63)
  - Benton, A. J., undated (Box-folder 2: 64)
  - Berger, Joseph, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 65)
  - Berger, Peter L., 1979 (Box-folder 2: 66)
  - Berger, Y., 1962 (Box-folder 2: 67)
  - Berlin, Freies, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 68)
  - Berlin, Isaiah, 1960, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 69)
  - Berlinder, Joseph S., 1959 (Box-folder 2: 70)
  - Berlinguer, Signor S., 1971 (Box-folder 2: 71)
  - Bernard, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 2: 72)
  - Bernard, Jessie, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 73)
  - Bernard, John, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 74)
  - Berry, M. J., 1963 (Box-folder 2: 75)
  - Berselli, Geovanne, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 76)
  - Bertino, Alesandra, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 77)
  - Berton, Peter, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 78)
  - Bertrand, Frank C., 1970 (Box-folder 2: 79)
  - Bertsch, Gary K., 1976 (Box-folder 2: 80)
  - Besançon, Alain, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 81)
  - Besemeres, John, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 82)
  - Betaki, Vasili, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 83)
  - Betancourt, Antonio, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 84)
  - Bettiza, Enzo, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 2: 85)
  - Bevis, Alison, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 86)
  - Bezsonova, Sarah, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2: 87)
  - Bialas, F., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 88)
  - Bialer, Seweryn, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Bianco, Gino, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - de Bie, Pierre, 1962 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Bieber, Marion F., 1961-1976 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - de Biencourt, François, 1960 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Biggart, John, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Biggs, Anita, 1981 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Biggs-Davison, John, 1976 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Biran, Yoav, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Birnbaum, Henrik, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Birnbaum, Norman, 1959 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Black, Hilary K., 1972 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Blackwell, Vera, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Blake, Patricia, 1962-1986 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Blandford, Ardella E., 1963 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Blane, Andrew, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Blit, B. C., 1954 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Bloch, Lionel, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Bob, 1962 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Bobbio, Norberto, 1979 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Bociurkiw, Bohdan R., 1970 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Bogdanor, Vernon, 1986 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Bohm, Anne M., undated (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - Bokov, N., 1978 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Böll, Heinrich, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Bolling, Landrum, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Bolloten, Burnett, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Bonanni, Massimo, 1968 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - Bonavia, David, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - Bondy, François, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3: 30)
  - Bone, Christopher, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 31)
  - Bonella, Sandro, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 32)
  - Bonuzzi, P., 1961 (Box-folder 3: 33)
  - Borkowski, Piotr, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 3: 34)
  - Bott, Lydia, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 35)
  - Bourlatskii, Fedor, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 36)
  - Bourricaud, François, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3: 37)
  - Bowen, Carroll G., 1969 (Box-folder 3: 38)
  - Bowes, Paul, 1977 (Box-folder 3: 39)
  - Bowling, John, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 3: 40)
  - Boyle, Edward, 1969 (Box-folder 3: 41)
  - Braid, A. R., 1977 (Box-folder 3: 42)
  - Brancovan, Constantine, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 43)
  - Brand, Gerd, Dr., 1975-1978 (Box-folder 3: 44)
  - Brandon, Donald, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 45)
  - Brandstatter, Christian, 1969 (Box-folder 3: 46)
  - Braude, Beatrice, 1962 (Box-folder 3: 47)
  - Brennan, E. J., 1974 (Box-folder 3: 48)
  - Breth, Fred E., 1975 (Box-folder 3: 49)
  - Bretscher, H. C. W., Dr., 1980 (Box-folder 3: 50)
  - Brisby, Liliana, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 3: 51)
  - Brittan, Samuel, 1979 (Box-folder 3: 52)
  - Bromberg, Adam, Dr., 1973 (Box-folder 3: 53)
  - Bromke, Adam, 1961, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 3: 54)
  - Brooks, Jeffery, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 55)
  - Brostrom, Kenneth N., 1973 (Box-folder 3: 56)
  - Brown, Deming, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 57)
  - Brown, Edward J., 1969-1972 (Box-folder 3: 58)
  - Brown, Jim F., 1971 (Box-folder 3: 59)
  - Brown, Neville G., 1986 (Box-folder 3: 60)
  - Brown, Pamela, 1976 (Box-folder 3: 61)
  - Brown, Seyom, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 62)
  - Brownjohn, J. Maxwell, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 3: 63)
  - Bruegel, J. W., 1971-1974 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Brumberg, Abraham, 1958-1976 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Brunson, Michael, 1968 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Brus, W., 1981 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Bryan, undated (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Bryner, Cyril, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Bryson, Phillip, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Brzeski, Andrzej, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Brzeziński, Zbigniew, 1969-1985 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Buchan, Alistair, 1967 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Buchan, D., 1970, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Buchanan, Paul G., 1984-1985 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Buckley, W., 1977 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Budiman, Arief, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Bukovsky, Vladimir, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Bull, Roger L., 1963 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Bullock, Lord, undated (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Bundy, William, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Bune, W. G., 1969 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Burgess, P., 1969 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Burke, Thomas, Sir, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Burks, R. V., 1968 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Burmeister, W., 1974 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - Burnett, Frank, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - Burnett, K. R., 1968 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - Burns, Roger, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Burns, Tom, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Burton, Susan, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Butterfield, Peter, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Byers, Hugh James, III, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - Byrnes, Robert F., 1976-1978 (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Byrski, Zbigniew, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - B - general, 1956-1976 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - Cafagna, Luciano, 1968 (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - Caldecott, Oliver, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Caldwell, Lawrence T., 1976 (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Call, David, 1966 (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - Cammarano, Leonard, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 4: 38)
  - Campbell, Glenn, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 39)
  - Carmichael, Joel, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 40)
  - Carson, Peter, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 41)
  - Carter, Mark Bonham, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 4: 42)
  - Cartwright, John, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 43)
  - Caruana, I., 1970 (Box-folder 4: 44)
  - Carus, M. Blouke, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 45)
  - Carver, David, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 4: 46)
  - Carynnyk, Marco, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 47)
  - Casanova, Jean-Claude, 1971, 1979 (Box-folder 4: 48)
  - Cass, Frank, 1978 (Box-folder 4: 49)
  - Cate, Curtis, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 4: 50)
  - Cavazza, Fabio Luca, 1961 (Box-folder 4: 51)
  - Cazes, Bernard, 1960 (Box-folder 4: 52)
  - Chace, Barbara R., 1961 (Box-folder 4: 53)
  - Chalfont, Lord, 1986 (Box-folder 4: 54)
  - Chall, Leo P., 1960 (Box-folder 4: 55)
  - Chant, Michael, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 56)
  - Chapman, G., 1977 (Box-folder 4: 57)
  - Charles, S., 1960 (Box-folder 4: 58)
  - Charlton, John, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 59)
  - Chartraire, J., 1972, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 60)
  - Chasey, Pauline, 1961 (Box-folder 4: 61)
  - Chatterji, N., 1960 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Checinski, Michael, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Ch'en, Jerome, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Chenoweth, Eric, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Chenu, Roselyne, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Cherfas, Teresa, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Chickering, A. Lawrence, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Chickering, A. W., 1976 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Chmielovicz, Michal, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Chornovil, Vyacheslav, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Christensen, H. C., 1966 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Churba, Joseph, 1987 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1971 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Chymanovsky, Irina, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Cieplak, Tadeusz N., Dr., 1968 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Cifric, Ivan, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Ciołkosz, Adam, 1970 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Clark, Ann Paul, 1962 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Clarke, Merlyn J., 1971 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Clarke, R. A., 1969 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Clarke, Stephen, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Click, Nathan, 1970 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Coates, Jenny, 1968-1971, 1990 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    Scope and Contents
    The majority of the documents in this file are administrative correspondence sent out by Labedz's secretary. The bulk of the letters are responses to inquiries regarding papers submitted to Survey magazine for publication.
  - Coates, Ken, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Cock, Alan G., 1926, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Cogan, J., 1962 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Cohen, Barry Mendel, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Cohen, Emily, undated (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Cohen, Sigmund, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Cohen, Stephen F., 1971-1972, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Coleman, Nadine, 1970 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Coleman, Peter, 1979, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Collet's, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - Collins, Christine, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Collins, Leslie, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Collins Publishers, 1966-1990 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Colozzi, Paula, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Colquhoun, Patrick, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - Condick, Frances, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - Confino, Michael, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - Conolly, Madeline, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - Conquest, Robert, 1963-1981 (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - Constable Publishers, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - Coors, 1981 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - Cornell, Richard, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 46)
  - Coser, Lewis A., 1960 (Box-folder 5: 47)
  - Courtois, N., 1974 (Box-folder 5: 48)
  - Couwenberg, S. W., Dr., 1971 (Box-folder 5: 49)
  - Cox and Kings (Agents) Limited, 1963 (Box-folder 5: 50)
  - Cox, Priscilla, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 51)
  - Craig, G. A., 1971 (Box-folder 5: 52)
  - Craker, Trevor, 1960 (Box-folder 5: 53)
  - Crankshaw, Edward, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 5: 54)
  - Cranston, Maurice, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 5: 55)
  - Criner, Lynn, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 56)
  - Croan, Melvin, 1960-1985 (Box-folder 5: 57)
  - Cronin, Anthea, 1963 (Box-folder 5: 58)
  - Crouch, Colin, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 5: 59)
  - Crowley, Edward L., 1969 (Box-folder 5: 60)
  - Crozier, Brian, 1962 (Box-folder 5: 61)
  - Crozier, Michel, 1970, 1979 (Box-folder 5: 62)
  - Crumpacker, Amy, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 63)
  - Curtis, Michael, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 64)
  - Cviic, Chris, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 5: 65)
  - Cybulska, Maja, E., 1970 (Box-folder 5: 66)
  - Czajkowski, Bogdan, 1960 (Box-folder 5: 67)
  - Czernichowski, Adam, 1986 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Czugunow, Vladimir, 1979 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Czyżowski, A., 1986 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - C - general, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Dadlez, Alina, 1962, 1968, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Dadrian, U. N., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Dagley, B. L., 1957 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Dahrendorf, Ralf, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Daiches, David, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Dallin, Alexander, 1962-1976 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Dandeker, Christopher, 1986 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Daniels, Robert V., 1959-1960 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Danuta, 1972 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - David, 1970, 1976 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Davies, John B., 1977 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Davies, R. W., 1958 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Davis, Donald E., 1969 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Davis, Eileen, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Davis, Joseph, Dr., undated (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Davis, Kingsley, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Davis, P. D. C., 1977 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Davis, Paul K., 1973 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Davy, Charles, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Davy, Richard, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Dawson, Tom, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Day, Alan J., 1970 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Day files, 1967-1983
    Comprised of correspondence with and regarding Survey magazine. When possible, Labedz's original order was maintained.
    - 1967 (Box-folder 6: 27)
    - 1968 February - August (Box-folder 6: 28-29)
    - 1968 September - 1969 July (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
    - 1969 August - 1970 September (Box-folder 7: 3-5)
    - 1970 October - 1972 March (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
    - 1972 April - 1973 September (Box-folder 8: 3-4)
    - 1973 September - 1974 September (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - 1975 September - 1976 September (Box-folder 9: 5, 10: 1)
    - 1976 September - 1977 September (Box-folder 10: 2-3)
    - 1977 September - 1978 December (Box-folder 10: 4-5)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 11: 6, 12: 1)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 12: 2-3)
  - Dean, Robert, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - DeAngelis, Alexander P., 1979 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Decter, Midge, 1979 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Dedijer, Steven, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Dee, Ivan R., 1971 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Degras, Jane, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Delaney, Donald J., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Demarest, Michael, 1968 (Box-folder 12: 11)